DAN URSON

SECURITY ENGINEER

CONTACT

+1 703 996 6691

https://plygrnd.net

Trenton, Michigan, USA

SKILLS

Security Operations/Incident Response

Crisis Communication

Scripting and Automation

Forensics and Threat Hunting

Automation and prototyping

EDUCATION

Culinary Arts

Silwood Kitchen

2009-2011

High School Diploma

Herzlia High School

2005-2007

LANGUAGES

English Afrikaans



Hebrew

Provided mer from Associa Developed ar process error time/month. Responsible

OVERVIEW

Self-taught security professional with 10+ years' experience in security engineering, customer service, and platform abuse mitigation. Focused on automation, incident response, and stakeholder engagement. Specialist in Coordinated Vulnerability Disclosure (CVD). Co-founded Amazon Web Services' (AWS) Outreach team, responsible for CVD across the company, and developed its first CVE issuance benchmark framework. Coordinated AWS's response to several high-profile security issues. Reduced manual work on specific process by 90% and decreased error rate for this process to 0%. Experienced Python developer.

Legally authorized to work in the European Union and South Africa

WORK EXPERIENCE

Security Engineer

Amazon Web Services

2016-2023

- Co-founded AWS's security research community engagement effort. Grew and nurtured
 a large community of trusted security research professionals and built significant trust
 in AWS as a vulnerability research partner.
- Acted as incident commander for embargoed security issue, coordinating multiple stakeholders across lines of business to prevent impact to AWS before public release.
- Provided mentorship and training to junior engineers. Helped promote two engineers from Associate Engineer to Engineer 1 within 9 months.
- Developed an internal tool to automate a complex, risky internal process. Reduced process error rate to 0% and execution time by 90%. Saved 250 hours of engineer time/month.
- Responsible for publication of 14 AWS Security Bulletins and mitigating impact of each related issue before publication. Required coordination across multiple AWS teams including senior leadership up to CEO level
- Led AWS's response to three major customer incidents requiring 24/7 focus.
 Restructured team runbooks to reflect lessons learned during engagement. Built automated log analysis framework to speed up such engagements.
- Rewrote team's entire internal knowledge base (~900 wiki pages) and consolidated into single new platform based on Sphinx.

Trust and Safety specialist

Amazon Web Services

2014-2016

- Developed new processes for limiting impact of DoS attacks to AWS customers (reduced mitigation time to 30 seconds from 4 minutes)
- Grew team from 4 to 35 people by 2016 based on business need to handle case load
- Subject matter expert: email/text spam
- Liaised with external IP reputation providers (Spamhaus and Trend Micro) to improve AWS's IP reputation. Reduced spam incidence by 94%.
- Highest accuracy rating for mitigations in team (100% over 6 months)
- · Seconded to US office in 2014 to develop team's skills
- Promoted to lead T&S specialist for EMEA

DAN URSON

SECURITY ENGINEER

CONTACT

+1 703 996 6691

dan@plygrnd.net

https://plygrnd.net

Trenton, Michigan, USA

https://github.com/plygrnd

https://linkedin.com/in/durson

EXPERTISE

- · Crisis Communication and PR
- · Web application security assessment
- · Relationship management
- Executive communication including briefings for senior leaders up to and including CEOs
- · Log analysis at scale
- Community engagement
- Python development
- · Rapid application prototyping
- Customer communication
- · Technical writing
- Interpersonal development/mentoring
- Learning/development/selfeducation
- SIEM integration and data management
- Infrastructure as Code within Amazon Web Services (Terraform/CloudFormation/Cloud Development Kit)
- Secure Software Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Billing Specialist

Amazon Web Services 2014

Short tenure in this position before moving to Trust and Safety team

Customer Service Associate

2012-2014 Amazon

- Hired as temporary/seasonal contact centre associate during the 2012 holiday season. Hired permanently in February 2013.
- Founded Amazon Locker customer service team:
 - liaised with business and engineering teams to solve customer problems
 - o Built functional specifications for tools required by customer service associates to troubleshoot problems with locker units
 - o Developed knowledge content for locker operations and customer service which is still in use today.

PROJECTS

- SCRY: Internal tool used to aid teams in developing security-focused communication
- Custom report generator for previous team, which generated oncall stats and reduced time in process from 20 minutes to 30 seconds
- Termination automation which saved ~250 hours of work each month for security operations team
- Amazon Locker customer service launch



